Thomas Bridge

39 Hare Bridge Crescent, Ingatestone, Essex, CM4 9DR +44 7968 155586 tbridge@chicagobooth.edu

SUMMARY

An experienced technologist with proven success in both technical design and leading teams across the product life cycle. In depth technical knowledge and skills combined with business acumen offers a unique strength that provides for a competitive edge in a dynamic business environment. Proven success working across geographically diverse regions in Europe and Asia Pacific for both European and American firms, demonstrating the ability to adapt equally well to new technologies, business thinking and cultural environments. A demonstrated flair for picking up new quantitative and analytical skills and a strong believer in lifelong learning.

EXPERIENCE

TRAFIGURA, London (Contract)

April 2017 – Present

Trafigura is one of the world's leading independent commodity trading and logistics houses.

Network Consultant

Trafigura outsourced their network operations environment to an offshore team based in India. My role is to act as the bridge between that team and the network engineering team driven primarily out of their London office. The role is focused on driving operation improvements and upskilling the remote team so that the network engineering team can focus on more development work.

DATAPIPE, London Feb 2015 – March 2017

Datapipe are a leading solutions provider for managing critical IT services based on datacenter and cloud solutions. Headquartered in New Jersey, they provide services around the world.

Regional Network Manager EMEA

Responsible for managing a team of network engineers based in Datapipe's London office with a view to driving service improvements. In this role I provided leadership on both the management and the technical side of the business.

- Interviewing, selecting and mentoring several new team members
- Designing and enforcing the change control processes using ITIL frameworks.
- Produced a new set of reports as we started to quantify the performance of the network team.
- Emphasizing the importance of following the correct human resource processes.
- Managing the delivery of key customer projects looking at both architecture and delivery components of the network solution.
 - Key design authority and technical lead on a major hybrid cloud and data centre project for a large client, including building a proof of concept, their first major European buildout and then providing a choice of designs for their US East Coast expansion.
 - ASA Contexts, VRFs, Nexus 9ks and AWS components.
 - o Drove a major network realignment for a separate client as we rebuilt the core of their network around our Data Centres in all three geographies.
- Providing technical expertise to the team on configuration and troubleshooting.
- Did some scripting including rewriting a Python script used for generating lists of devices
- Evaluated and installed a number of NMS platforms in order to assess their usefulness including Observium and SolarWinds.
- Delivering hybrid cloud solutions with AWS, Azure, private cloud and dedicated datacenter components.
- Developed an ASA configuration generator in PHP.
- Helped reduce latency across the network by rerouting traffic over faster links.

EQUIDUCT, London Oct 2013 – Feb 2015

Equiduct is a pan European Trading Market, operated by Borse Berlin.

IT Operations Manager

Responsible for managing the operations of the technology environment with additional responsibilities for the network.

- Managing multiple vendors with responsibility for parts of the infrastructure and managing the internal IT function.
- Reducing costs on mobile telephony by 50% by detailed analysis of the phone bills.
- Responsible for the full range of services within Equiduct from desktop to core infrastructure.
- As the sole network engineer in the organization, I was responsible for managing firewall and networking changes as appropriate.

CINCINNATI BELL TECHOLOGY SOLUTIONS (CBTS), Singapore (Contract) Feb 2010 – June 2013 CBTS are a fully owned subsidiary of Cincinnati Bell, a regional telco focused on the greater Cincinnati area. CBTS deliver IT solutions to key businesses, including major contracts with two Fortune 50 companies across North America, Europe and Asia.

Asia Pacific Network Operations Manager

Assigned to the GE Global Account. Focused on expanding the support for several GE businesses to reflect the needs of the businesses in the Asia Pacific region and globally.

- Manage the client relationship in region and drive projects for greater service improvement.
- Interviewed and selected candidates for replacement and new roles.
- Mentored the team in both technical and business development (one achieved CCIE). Including emphasizing the importance of adhering to ITIL principles.
- Lead technical discussions and communications to business users during major outages.
- Working with other technical teams to drive faster incident resolution.
- Analyzed and drove improvements to the global team's performance on incident handling, raising the SLA target achievement from 90% to 97%.
- Reorganized the existing resources in Asia Pacific to be part of the wider CBTS operations team improving the efficiency of the team and keeping my partner in GE very happy.
- Analyzed and reported on data to drive improvements in the incident handling process example was identifying a trend in incorrect tickets being sent to our team and taking steps resulting a reduction of 20 tickets a week.
- Liaised with Network designers and application teams to discuss and manage the challenges around latency and performance in particular emphasizing the specific challenges of the ASPAC region.

TOUCHBASE, London, UK (Contract)

Oct 2009 - Jan 2010

Touchbase are a leading supplier of IP networking and telephony solutions to enterprises.

Network Consultant

A short term contract providing consultancy and support services to CSR, a leading manufacturer of wireless chips

 Documented and implemented a new network design to facilitate their integration after a recent merger, reducing the complexity and time involved in supporting the network so that required resources for the network was reduced by 50%

BT RADIANZ, London, UK

May 2006 – Aug 2009

Radianz (acquired by BT in 2005) provides a neutral third party extranet to the financial services sector to provide connectivity between content providers and consumers.

Senior Project Engineer

Delivered customized solutions to large financial information providers (including Thomson Reuters and Merrill Lynch).

- Liaised with project managers within Radianz and the customer, ensuring their needs were fully understood and delivered.
- Documented network designs and presentations for multiple projects, including delivery of training for those new designs on site in London and Singapore as well as online.
- Designed and built a 6 9s (99.9999%) available network for key applications (normal standard is 5 9s 99.999%) this was the key deliverable for a large 8 digit contract.
- Examined and adapted a key trading platform network.
- Collaborated on process improvements for more efficient rollouts of projects.

INTEROUTE, London, UK

May 2005 – Apr 2006

Interoute are a Europe wide telecoms company who own one of the largest private fibre networks in Europe, delivering innovative and cutting edge networking products and services to businesses across Europe.

Network Architect

Worked on the core IP/MPLS network. Responsible for developing the core, as well as maintaining a number of internal networks and working on product development with Product managers.

- Drove the completion of an internal network rollout that had stalled for eight months before joining completing the project inside three months enabling the rollout of a new fiber ring service against an expectation it would take six months.
- Documented new products at a technical level enabling two new products to be launched.,

MESH BROADBAND, Essex, UK

Nov 2004 – Apr 2005

A small wireless ISP start up. Mesh had two small wireless networks in rural parts of England and were tendering for more.

Network Manager

Led a small team of engineers supporting a wireless network, as well as producing designs and pricing for proposed projects that the company was bidding for.

- Implemented new security and access policies to the existing network.
- Completely overhauled the design for a proposed core network reducing the proposed capital costs by 50%.

NETSOURCE, Dublin, Ireland

Feb 1996 - October 2004

Irish ISP in the startup stage. Initially Medianet, the company was acquired by VIA NET.WORKS Inc. in 1999 and then subsequently resold to the original management in 2002.

Network and Systems Architect (September 2002 – Oct 2004)

- Developed the first independent DSL service in Ireland with a product turning over €1million a year.
- Networked and created brand awareness within the Irish technical community generating leads for a number of customers requiring DSL services with a very high conversion rate.
- Recruited and trained a new tech support department, completing the project two months earlier than scheduled, resulting in customers reporting greater happiness with the support services supplied.
- Managed the relationship with multiple vendors to ensure costs were kept at a minimum saving the costs by up to €50k

Head of Network Operations Centre (June 2000 – September 2002)

Managed the network and systems in Ireland and additional support for the UK network, including integrating the Irish and UK networks into one.

Systems Administrator (February 1999 – June 2000)

Support of the systems for the separate Irish company. Advanced provisioning of customer services.

Technical Support (Feb 1996 – September 1998)

Handling customer technical queries and providing solutions. Provisioning of customer services.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CHICAGO BOOTH SCHOOL OF BUSINESS,

March 2013

Master of Business Administration – awarded with Honors.

OPEN UNIVERSITY, United Kingdom

November 2010

Bachelor of Science, Computing and Statistics (First class honours)

TRINITY COLLEGE DUBLIN, Ireland

June 2001

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING AND AFFILIATIONS

IT Related Certifications AWS Advanced Networking Specialist 2017 AWS Certified Sysops Administrator 2017 AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate 2017 AWS Certified Developer Associate 2017 ITIL V3 Foundations 2011 CCIE (Routing and Switching) #14108 (currently Emeritus) 2004 CCNP (expired) 2002 CCNA(expired) 2001

Other technical areas: HP Switches, Juniper, Linux, Windows, Databases

Reporting: Used Excel, Access, VBA, Oracle SQL to generate reports

Programming: Online courses from Coursera in R and Ruby. Used Perl for automation of systems and network tasks. Created an ASA firewall config generator in PHP. Python.

PUBLICATIONS

"That's the Ticket! Redesigning an Online Customer Support System in an Internet Company" (2001) AMCIS 2001 Proceedings. Paper 177. (with Diana Wilson, Paul Deasy and Alan Whelan)